<blog>
	<post>
		<date>April 10, 2023</date>
		<author>Mahesh R</author>
		<title>AWS S3 Multi-Region Access Points</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:828/format:webp/1*wqvavqwIjMC3dNav92rbfw.png</image_path>
			<text>Amazon S3 is an Object Storage service that provides virtually unlimited storage for all your file storage needs. As an added feature, you can configure a storage bucket for versioning to keep the files based on the update made to it.</text>
		</summary>
		<body>Amazon S3 Multi-Region Access Points offer a global S3 hostname that provides access to multiple S3 buckets across AWS Regions with automatic routing and failover between buckets. Requests made to an S3 Mutli-Region Access Point global host name are routed and accelerated across AWS Global Accelerator network. Requests will be served by bucket with lowest latency.</body>
	</post>
	<post>
		<date>April 10, 2023</date>
		<author>Mahesh R</author>
		<title>AWS S3 Multi-Region Access Points</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:828/format:webp/1*wqvavqwIjMC3dNav92rbfw.png</image_path>
			<text>Amazon S3 is an Object Storage service that provides virtually unlimited storage for all your file storage needs. As an added feature, you can configure a storage bucket for versioning to keep the files based on the update made to it.</text>
		</summary>
		<body> After logging into your AWS Console, under Services > All Services, search for “S3” and click on it to go to the S3 dashboard.
On the S3 DashMake sure you create the buckets in different AWS Region, and Enable Bucket Versioning.
board, click on the Create Bucket button to create a new storage bucket.
Enter the bucket name. The name has to be globally unique, so just try with another name if you get an error “Bucket with the same name already exists”.
Leave all other settings intact & click on the Create bucket button at the bottom of the page
</body>
	</post>
<post>
		<date>April 10, 2023</date>
		<author>Mahesh R</author>
		<title>AWS S3 Multi-Region Access Points</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:828/format:webp/1*wqvavqwIjMC3dNav92rbfw.png</image_path>
			<text>Amazon S3 is an Object Storage service that provides virtually unlimited storage for all your file storage needs. As an added feature, you can configure a storage bucket for versioning to keep the files based on the update made to it.</text>
		</summary>
		<body> Now follow the same steps from Step 1 b) to e) but this time change the name of the bucket, and change the region to any of your choice (I am creating in Ireland).
Creating the Multi-Region Access Points

a) Select the Multi-Region Access Points on the left pane of S3 Dashboard.

b) Now click on Create Multi-Region Access Point to create MRAP.
Enter a Access Point name which is unique, make sure to set a clear name as this can’t be edited after MRAP is created.

d) Click on Add buckets and select both buckets to add the buckets to MRAP
</body>
	</post>
</blog>
	